Hey everyone, and thanks for dropping
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about
Bitcoin, and we're going to be
discussing the social risk. If you guys
like the content, make sure you
subscribe to the channel, give the video
a thumbs up, and also check out the sale
on Into the Cryptoverse Premium at
intothecryptoverse.com.
If you didn't get a chance to check out
the recent Bitcoin cycle memo that we
published in July, I would encourage you
to go take a look at that, as I think it
does a good job of tying all the pieces
together, and it's absolutely free to
read if you're curious about where I
think we are within the cycles, and
you'd prefer to read something rather
than hear me just talk about it. So, go
read that if you are in fact interested.
Bitcoin right now is trading for around
$64,000,
but there is still this sense of like
apathy in the air. Like, even if Bitcoin
does go up a little bit more,
um
I I still feel like there's this this
sense of apathy, and when you look at at
the social interest, you can see it was
about 0.25. Now, the last bear market in
July, social interest was actually about
double what it is right now. It was
actually closer to like 0.5, whereas in
2018, it was actually closer to 0.25,
where we are at this current time. And
what's fascinating is the social
interest is about the same, and then the
market structure is about the same as it
was in 2018, right? Finding support at
60k in 2026, finding support at 6k in
2018. Bitcoin putting in a low in
February of 2018, and then sweeping that
low in late June. Same thing in 2026,
low in February, sweeping that low in
like late June, early July. You got your
lower highs in in May, um
and your higher lows in late March,
early April. It's all basically the same
thing. And when you look at the social
interest, it's also very very similar.
So, I would continue to say, "Look,
until proven otherwise, this is what's
happening." And frankly, there are
dozens of us left at this point. Because
when you think about the social risk
being this low, we can go through like
the different constituents of it. It's
made up of Google Trends, the relative
ranking of the Coinbase app, YouTube
subscribers, YouTube views, followers to
various analysts on X
that talk about Bitcoin and crypto and
exchanges and layer ones. So, one of
those is YouTube views. And you can see
that in our heyday, we were averaging 3
to 4 million views a day, not just my
channel, but all these channels that you
see listed down here. And today, they're
only averaging around 358,000
views a day. So, they've literally
dropped an order of magnitude
over the last 5 years.
Okay?
And that drop also helps explain why
when you look at charts like the
advanced decline index of the top 100
cryptocurrencies, that's also been going
down since 2021. So, it all makes sense
when you think about it. Like social
interest has been drying out since 2021.
And the advanced decline index of the
top 100 cryptocurrencies has been going
down. You might say, "Well, what about
the bull market?" Yeah, we had a bull
market for Bitcoin, but a lot of
altcoins didn't have a bull market. In
fact, a lot of altcoins just continued
to go down. And it was just a few
altcoins that went up that that kind of
lifted the total market cap of of the
altcoin space, but a lot of them did not
even put in new all-time highs. And now,
a lot of those altcoins are actually
below their 2022 lows rather than
trading near their 2021 highs. Um
So, it it really is interesting to see
the divergence. And when you look at
Bitcoin dominance uh excluding stables,
it is still relatively elevated, you
know? And and honestly, continues to
kind of go up. I know if you look at it
including stables, it looks like it's
dropping, but when you exclude stables,
dominance, you know, dominance has still
been generally trending higher, and it's
just because there's not a lot of people
left in the space right now. So, YouTube
views is one. You can also look at
YouTube subscribers to those same crypto
and or Bitcoin YouTube channels and see
they're averaging around 285 new
subscribers a day across all of these
channels. Compare that to 2021, and they
were averaging 50 to 60,000 a day at the
heights.
Again,
50 to 60,000 a day
versus 300 a day.
You can kind of understand why there's
the why Bitcoin dominance has been going
up, why the advanced kind of index of
the top 100 cryptocurrencies has been
going down. You can understand all of
it, right? In terms of like what went
wrong and why there was no rotation into
alts. How can you have a rotation into
alts if no one's here, you know? So,
look at the social interest. You can
also look
at followers to various and you can say,
"Well, what if it's just YouTube
specific? What if they change change
something?" And but no, it's across
platforms. If you look at followers to
various analysts on X,
um you can see they're averaging around
4,000 new followers a day, but in 2021,
they were averaging over 100,000
a day. So, we're at 1/20th of that level
back then.
If you look at, say, followers to
various layer ones,
you know, over the last several years,
you'll also see they're averaging around
8,000 new followers per day, whereas in
2021, they were averaging between, say,
at the heights over 100,000 a day. So,
less than 10% of what it was at the
height. And then, of course, you can
also look at
uh various sentiment metrics. We can
look at Google Trends, like search
interest. I think that's an interesting
one. And you can see that it really
never got going this cycle, right? Like
it it it honestly just hasn't been what
I think a lot of people
thought it was going to be.
So, that's your your social your social
stuff. You can also look at at some of
the different sentiment metrics. Um
if you look at the sentiment metrics for
crypto asset weighted sentiment, it's
been generally trending down since 2021.
Um and then you can also look at
Wikipedia page views. If If anyone's
into that kind of thing, I mean, I'm not
going to to Wikipedia to to learn about
Bitcoin, but some people are, right? And
in 2017 they did, and in 2021 they did,
and they didn't really do that this
cycle.
So, again, clearly a major difference
between this cycle and and the last two.
So, frankly, there are dozens of us left
at this point. Dozens. And my guess is
the social interest will continue to go
down before it goes back up.
I'm hoping to see it maybe bottom a
little bit later this year, perhaps
early next year.
It seems like we might be getting to
some pretty low levels. I'd like to
think that after you have two bear
markets, you could hopefully start to
see it trend back up without that
euphoric rally. Hopefully we do get a
euphoric rally next cycle, but we're
obviously too early to know that right
now. But let's see Let's see if this if
it can actually form a low sometime in
the next 6-12 months. And as I said,
there's dozens of us left, and those
dozens of us may be more than a few
dozen, but uh are hopefully going to the
first ITC conference, right? So, we are
having the first ITC conference uh later
this year in November. So, I hope to see
the remaining dozens of people there,
and we can talk about the markets, and
and talk about what are the expectations
going into the pre-halving year.
Thank you guys for tuning in. Make sure
you subscribe. I'll see you guys next
time. Bye.